The last time Virgil Tibbs had a day like this was "In the Heat of the Night"
They Call Me Mister Tibbs! is a drama, action,
thriller film directed by Gordon Douglas.
A police detective's investigation of a prostitute's
murder points to his best friend.
Virgil Tibbs, played by Sidney Poitier.
Logan Sharpe, played by Martin Landau.
Valerie Tibbs, played by Barbara McNair.
Rice Weedon, played by Anthony Zerbe.
Woody Garfield, played by Ed Asner.
Captain Marden, played by Jeff Corey.
They Call Me Mister Tibbs!
is a 1970 American DeLuxe Color crime drama film directed by Gordon Douglas.
The second installment in a trilogy, the release was preceded by In the Heat
of the Night (1967) and followed by The Organization (1971).
The film's title was taken from a line in the first film.
Sidney Poitier reprised his role of police detective Virgil Tibbs, though in this sequel, Tibbs is working for the San Francisco
Police rather than the Philadelphia Police (as in the original film) or the Pasadena Police (as in the novels).
The tone is mind_bending and emotional and intense.